

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

### **Details**

Bengaluru India +91 7980076336 ava10121994@gmail.com

NATIONALITY Indian

10-12-1994

### Links

LinkedIn

# **Skills**

Putty

Splunk

GitHub

UDeploy

HTML

CSS

Microsoft Office

ForgeRock

Rally

**AutoCAD** 

Ability to Multitask

Effective Time Management

Ability to Work in a Team

Leadership Skills

Adaptability

Knowledgable in User Interface/ User Experience

# Languages

Bengali

English

Hindi

# **Profile**

Versatile developer with over 4+ years of leveraging software engineering and implementing new technologies to maximize development efficiency. Conducting extensive market and consumer research to translate into application features. Acquiring and applying new complex technology concepts in short period of time.

# **Employment History**

# Application Development Analyst, Accenture, Bangalore

JANUARY 2021 - PRESENT

#### Client- Hartford

#### Single Front Door: JAN'21-MAY'21

- 1. Accomplished front end development in design/development methodologies using angular JS, HTML, CSS.
- 2. Involved in various agile software development like tasking out and effort estimation, developing, testing and defect fixing
- 3. Following coding standards for quality delivery (wrote Karma test cases), raising issue of blockers in stand up and retrospection. Completed assigned module.

### Customer Identity and Access Management JUN'21- Present

- 1. Analyzing and solving reported issue by creating query in Splunk to debug and find solution from the error logs.
- 2. Monitoring and providing stable environment for live user to have smooth experience with BMC Helix, Dynatrace.
- 3. Migrating different line of businesses with the application to provide secure account creation experiences ( single credentials for all account)
- 4. Working on Forgerock tool(IDM and AM) to support functionality of Customer Identity and Access Management providing Authorization roles, MFA federation, SAML2.0, SSO, OAuth
- 5. Working on tools like Rally, Jenkins, UDeploy, GitHub, SoapUI. Adequate knowledge on Unix/Linux language on PUTTY

### Application Development Associate, Accenture, Bangalore

DECEMBER 2018 - DECEMBER 2020

#### Client- NBN

Network Designing: DEC'18-JUL'19

- 1. Design flow of network with easy connections options for new customer maintaining quality standard
- 2. Single offhandedly delivered 50+ new design under all type of network architecture with minimal defects

### Quality Improvement Analysis: AUG'19-JUN'20

- 1. Delivered as a subject matter expert in development of programs under different internal teams that focuses on business practices that result in improving data reliability and validity
- 2. Ensuring that contractors are met the quality standards by communicating process errors providing all necessary support in order to fulfill the deliverables

### Rapid Resolution Assessment Center: JUL'20-DEC-'20

- 1. Analysis the problem facing by client in existing development area
- 2. Assessment of the feasibility of the solution and designing best possible way considering minimum and provide best services to the client in near future.

# Education

Masters in Computer Application , Academy of Technology, Hooghly

Bachelor in Computer Science, University of Calcutta, Kolkata

JULY 2012 - JUNE 2015